# **Andrew Bay**

### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

▼ victoryfox1116@gmail.com

% https://github.com/victoryfox1116

9013138516

#### About me

I am a highly self-motivated Web & Mobile Developer who spends most of my time building applications, learn from others and keeping myself up-to-date with the latest technologies.

With 8 years of experience in developing websites, web applications, and online tools for large companies and businesses, I can analyze your requirements and business ideas in the correct way and give you creative and efficient solutions that I can implement.

### Education

From April 2011 to September 2014

### Bachelor's Degree

Czech Technical University Prague

- Information Technology
- Get Bachelor's Degree

## Work experience

From February

### MernStack Developer

2022 to July 2022 Decagon Finance United States(Worked Remotely)

- Worked as a solo founding engineer aiding the company founder to build out a MVP for SASS platform to assist investors with unique opportunities to invest in private companies in
- Designed the entire architecture of the platform using React(TypeScript) and implemented modern web technologies to established the TDD flow from idea to MVP in a fast paced environment.

From August 2021 to March 2022

### **Lead Frontend Developer**

**Hubble Axiom United Kingdom(Worked Remotely)** 

- Lead Frontend developer building an Application using React(TypeScript), taking advantage of the AntDesign Framework for Frontend
- Deploy Webhook using Websocket so alert daily notification if there is change
- Ensuring the use Sagas and Redux-Thunk for state management.

From September

# Lead Web and Mobile Developer

2020 to July 2021 Yixin Academy Singapore(Worked Remotely)

- Developed SSR web-app using Node, MySQL and React(TypeScript).- Improved security using JWT Authentication and Middleware.
- Hosted the website using AWS, Complete Video Encrypt using AES and Payment integration with PayPal, Payoneer, and Credit Cards.
- Built the Application using Flutter and integrated fingerprints, QR codescan, Encrypt Video, Tracking Locations and Chat Rooms using Firebase.

### Contact

28 years old

American

Kansas

Single

Languages

# English

Can Speak Fluently

#### Czech

Mother Tongue Language

#### Skills

WebHook

MERN STACK

React Native | Flutter

Vue.js

Laravel

**MEAN STACK** 

Rust

Web3 | Solana/Web3

Solidity

From November 2019 to August 2020

### Web and Mobile Lead Developer

FutureLab New Zealand(Worked Remotely)

- Worked as Web and Mobile app developer, completing a total of 3 projects for Web by using Node, React native JS+Redux with Material UI(React native JS).- Completion of 1 React native app which was developed with UI as well as managing the data using Redux and Redux-Thunk as middleware to manage Asynchronous data.
- Responsible for checking cross browser compatibility and ensured the compatibility on different browsers such as Safari, Opera, Firefox, Google Chrome and Internet Explorer.
- Resolved complex issues related to browser and network performance, cross-browser and legacy IE compatibility, client-side scaling, data modeling, usability and testability
- Deep understanding and working experience in Object Oriented JavaScript programming and JavaScript Spring MVC frameworks.
- Expert in React native Js development and have experience React(TypeScript/Javascript), Angular, Responsive design.

From August

### Web Developer

2016 to July 2018 Alfuhod Kuwait(Worked Remotely)

- Expertise in React JS framework to develop the SPA- Completed the project using Redux architecture Object-Oriented concepts to improve the performance of the websites and developing an interactive UI using React JS components, Forms, Events, Router, and Animations.
- Developing in React.js to ensure interactive UI's using One-way data flow, Virtual DOM, JSX, React Native concepts
- Built Backend using Node.js and Express

to July 2016

# From March 2014 Working As A Freelancer

Freelancer & Upwork Global

- Worked as a Freelancer for improving my skills and expanding my network.
- Built Shopify, Mern, Laravel, and WordPress
- Experienced in React Native and Flutter for build Mobile Applications.